Finding Aid for the Kenneth Rexroth Papers LSC.0175
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Manuscripts by Rexroth, 1922-1976; 35 boxes (17 linear ft.).
  - Subseries 3D: Poetry and verse,., 1922-1967; 9.5 boxes.
    - In Defense of the Earth--Annotated typescripts., 1950-1955.; 5 items. (Box 45, Folder 6-8)
      Incomplete, corrected, and master mss. First published in Sausalito by the Golden Goose Press, 1953; master version from later publication by New Directions, New York, 1956.
    - In Defense of the Earth--Galley proofs., ca. 1955.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Lacking title and copyright pages.
    - In Defense of the Earth / Homestead Called Damascus / 30 Spanish Poems., no date.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Binder.
    - In What Hour., ca. 1940.; 34 items. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Typescript, in mixed order and with some duplication. First published in New York by Macmillan, 1940.
    - Iphegenia at Aulis: a dance play., ca. 1945.; 4 items. (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Annotated typescripts.
    - Lament for Dylan Thomas., no date; ca. 1954.; 2 items. (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Annotated typescript of poem, and Greek translation.
    - Love is an Art of Time., no date.; 2 items. (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Typescript.
    - Miscellaneous--Poems., 1928-1966.; ca. 500 items. (Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50)
      Several long poems in mixed order and various stages of development; notes, possibly for poems or essays, also in mixed order, etc.; numerous short poems, most untitled, with miscellaneous notations. Many of the mss. appear incomplete, and the leaves have been filled on both sides. Typewritten and handwritten sheets, with corrections.
    - Mother Goose., no date.; 2 items. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Handwritten poems. First published as part of In Defense of the Earth, by the Golden Goose Press in Sausalito, 1953.
    - Natural Numbers., ca. 1963.; 2 items. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      Typescript. First published in New York by New Directions, 1963.
    - Notes for Orestaeia., 1946 - 51.; 1 item. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Old poems., no date.; 1 item. (Box 51, Folder 4)
      Folder labeled "Old Poems" containing approximately 200 annotated typescripts and handwritten poems.
    - Original Sin., ca. 1961.; 1 item. (Box 51, Folder 5)
      Typescript of ballet choreography; letter from James Laughlin.
    - Pacific Beach., 1962 November 1.; 1 item. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Handwritten and typescript versions. Included in Steuben Glass interpretation of poetry, Poetry in Crystal, 1962.
    - Phaedra: a dance play., 1944.; 4 items. (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Annotated typescripts, pencil drawings.
    - The Phoenix and the Tortoise., ca. 1944.; 4 items. (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Annotated typescripts and notes. First published in Norfolk, Conn., by New Directions, 1944. Includes most of the poems in the final version, in mixed order. First leaf inscribed, "Marie's copy."
    - Poems., ca. 1939.; 4 items. (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
      Folders of poetry. Includes work from In What Hour, and a version of the essay The Function of the Poet in Society, plus unpublished pieces.
    - Poems., 1939.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
      Folders of poetry.
    - Poems for Jazz., ca. 1960.; 7 items. (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Annotated typescript.
    - Selected Poems of Kenneth Rexroth., no date.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Photostat list of poem titles.
    - The Signature of All Things., 1948-1949.; 2 items. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Annotated typescript, plus galley proofs. Many of the poems have notes by Rexroth about previous publication. First published in New York by New Directions, 1950.
    - Sky Sea Birds Trees Earth House Beasts Flowers., 1970.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 6)
      Typescript; includes Rexroth's translations of two poems by Jules Supervielle.
    - A Song at the Winepresses., no date.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - The Spark in the Tinder of Knowing., no date.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 8)
      Typescript. Published by Pym-Randall Press, 1968.
    - The Thin Edge of Your Pride., 1922-1925.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 9)
      Typescript, for Leslie Smith.
  - Subseries 3E: Prose,., 1935-1976; 18 boxes.
    Arranged alphabetically, where possible, by the given title of the manuscript or published work, with the exception of magazine articles. "Miscellaneous" folders contain manuscripts that were filed together by Rexroth in unlabeled folders, and the original order was preserved at the time of processing.
    - Alienation., 1967 August 24.; 1 item. (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Typescript essay for NY Times Book Review.
    - The Alternative Society., 1965-1969.; 4 items. (Box 54, Folder 2-4)
      Annotated typescripts and selections. See box 158 for oversize galley proofs.
    - American Poetry in the Twentieth Century., ca. 1971.; 1 item. (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Annotated typescript; see box 158 for oversize galley proofs.
    - American Poetry in the Twentieth Century., ca. 1971.; 8 items. (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
      Annotated typescript and reading list
    - The Arts In An Age of Anxiety., 1965 September 30.; 1 item. (Box 55, Folder 4)
      Typescript essay.
    - Assays., 1964.; 5 items. (Box 55, Folder 5-6)
      Carbon typescripts with handwritten annotations. As returned from the publisher, New Directions, in New York.
    - August Renoir art review., no date.; 2 items. (Box 55, Folder 7)
      Handwritten and typescript versions of essay.
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Rough draft off final tapes., no date.; 1 item. (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Semi-final draft., no date.; 1 item. (Box 56, Folder 4-5)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Semi-final draft., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit A (folder 1 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Chapters 1-3
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit A (folder 2 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Chapters 4-7
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit A (folder 3 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Chapters 8-10
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit A (folder 4 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Chapters 11-14
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit A (folder 5 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 6)
      Chapters 15-21
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit B (folder 1 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 57, Folder 7)
      Chapters 1-9
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit B (folder 2 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 1)
      Chapters 10-16
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit B (folder 3 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 2)
      Chapters 17-25
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit B (folder 4 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 3)
      Chapters 26-30
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Edit B (folder 5 of 5)., no date.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 4)
      Chapters 31-38
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 1 (folder 1 of 3)., 1959.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 5)
      Chapters 1-8
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 1 (folder 2 of 3)., 1959.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 6)
      Chapters 9-13
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 1 (folder 3 of 3)., 1959.; 1 item. (Box 58, Folder 7)
      Chapters 14-18
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 2 (folder 1 of 3)., 1961.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Chapters 19-28
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 2 (folder 2 of 3)., 1961.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      Chapters 29-34
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master, vol. 2 (folder 3 of 3)., 1961.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master Copy (folder 1 of 2)., 1963 October 1.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 4)
      Photocopied typescript. Chapters 1-25. See box 158 for an annotated galley proof.
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Master Copy (folder 2 of 2)., 1963 October 1.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 5)
      Photocopied typescript. Chapters 26-36.
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Early draft., no date.; 1 item. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Partial typescript 1., no date.; 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Partial typescript 2., 1961.; 4 items. (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Includes letters of criticism from Double Day editors.
    - An Autobiographical Novel--Introduction., 1965 August 17.; 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 3)
      Draft of introduction and supplementary material.
    - Autobiographical statement., no date.; 25 items. (Box 61, Folder 4)
      Photocopies of a three-page autobiographical statement.
    - BBC Lectures on the Beat Generation., 1966.; 7 items. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      Drafts and correspondence related to a lecture series.
    - Roger Blin theater review., 1956.; 2 items. (Box 61, Folder 6)
      Handwritten and typescript essay on Blin's version of Samuel Beckett's Godot.
    - Bird in the Bush., ca. 1959.; 2 items. (Box 61, Folder 7)
      Incomplete typescript and introduction.
    - Classics Revisited--Essays., no date.; ca. 100 items. (Box 61, Folder 8-10)
      Handwritten and typescript essays, annotated.
    - Classics Revisited, Volume I., 1967-1986.; 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 1)
      Typescripts, bound.
    - Classics Revisited, Volume II., 1968-1971.; 7 items. (Box 62, Folder 2)
      Typescript lists of subjects.
    - Collected Essays., 1958.; 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Typescripts, bound. Incomplete. Essays appear to be different versions of other essays in the collection.
    - Collected Longer Poems., ca. 1968.; 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Typescript, introduction.
    - Communalism: Its Origins to the Twentieth Century., no date.; 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Drafts of magazine articles., 1965-1966.; 10 items. (Box 63, Folder 1)
      Handwritten and typescript essays from a folder labeled "Drafts of magazine articles."
    - Draughts., 1968.; 12 items. (Box 63, Folder 2)
      Drafts and typescript essays from a folder labeled "1968".
    - Elastic Retort Section I & II., no date.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Typescript, bound.
    - Elastic Retort Section III., no date.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica., 1971-1973.; 5 items. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      Typescripts and bibliography for article on literature.
    - Four Young Women Poets., ca. 1973.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      Typescript introduction.
    - General essays., ca. 1971-1973.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 7)
      Typescripts removed from a binder with the same title.
    - Grace Cathedral., 1970.; ca. 10 items. (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Typescript of Rexroth's keynote address; correspondence and ephemera.
    - The Great American Conspiracy., no date.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      Outline.
    - Great Ideas Today., 1970.; 4 items. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      Proofs.
    - Guilt., 1967 August 29.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 3)
      Typescript article (for Playboy).
    - Hercules., no date.; 2 items. (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Heroic Tragedy and the Hero., 1935.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - History., no date.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 6)
      Typescript essays in a folder by the same title (mostly from Assays and Bird in the Bush).
    - How Poets Make A Living, If Any., 1966-1967.; 3 items. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Drafts, clipping of published article, and related questionnaire.
    - The Influence of French Poetry on American., 1958 November.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Introduction for Henry Miller., ca. 1952.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 9)
      Annotated typescript, "The neglected Henry Miller." First published in The Nation, v. 181, no. 19, Nov. 5, 1955, pp. 385-7. Published later as the introduction to Miller's Nights of Love and Laughter in paperback form by Signet.
    - Introduction for Kenneth Patchen., no date.; 2 items. (Box 64, Folder 10)
      Annotated typescripts, not known if published. Notation at top of first leaf reads: "to Selected Writings of Kenneth Patchen."
    - Introduction for Waite., 1960.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Annotated typescript for The Holy Kabbala.
    - Introduction for hippy (Time) book., 1967 August.; 2 items. (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Is There a Crisis of Public Morals? Of Private?., no date.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 13)
      Carbon typescript of essay.
    - Japanese literature., no date. (Box 64, Folder 14)
      Assorted essays on Japan and Japanese literature.
    - Japanese Show, San Francisco DeYoung Museum., 1951 September.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 15)
      Art review.
    - Jazz Poetry., 1958 February 17.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 16)
      Annotated typescript, in a hand other than Rexroth's.
    - Léger (Fernand) article., 1953 June.; 2 items. (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Lemennais., no date.; 2 items. (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Letter from America., 1946.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 19)
      Typescript of letter to George Woodcock, published as "Letter from America" in Now, London, v. 7 (Feb.-Mar.).
    - Little Anthology of Little Magazine Poets., 1954.; 2 items. (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Originally compiled for the New Republic, but not known if published. Includes poems by Denise Levertov, Leslie Woolf Hedley, Scott Greer, Cid Corman, Robert Duncan, Frederick Eckman, Robert Creeley, Richard Wirtz Emerson, Chris Bjerknes, Gill Orlovitz, Charles Olsen, Philip Lamantia, and commentary by Rexroth. Handwritten introduction; complete. typescript and correspondence.
    - Lonergan conference., ca. 1970.; 2 items. (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Typescripts.
    - Miscellaneous essays., ca. 1958-1970.; ca. 50 items. (Box 65, Folder 3-6)
      Assorted essays and articles for a variety of publishers.
    - Miscellaneous essays--Published., ca. 1969-1970.; 1 item. (Box 65, Folder 7)
      Typescripts of essays in cardboard binder.
    - Morals, Ethics, Religion, Ideology, the Poet, Poetry., no date.; 2 items. (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - New American Poets, 1957-1964., ca. 1964.; 2 items. (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - New British Poets., ca. 1946-1947.; ca. 200 items. (Box 66, Folder 2-7)
      Collection of individual manuscripts sent to Rexroth for inclusion in his anthology by the poets whose work he requested. Leaves are in mixed order with poems heavily annotated by the authors and in Rexroth's hand. Includes introduction.
    - New British Poets--Typescripts., ca. 1946-1949.; 2 items. (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
      Incomplete draft.
    - Notes for Modernists., no date.; ca. 10 items. (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Assorted notes.
    - Nous N'irons Plus au Bois: William Everson., no date.; 1 item. (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Typescript of article on William Everson.
    - The Objectivism of Edward Weston., 1931 November.; 3 items. (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Outline for Gainsborough Time- Life Library of Art., 1967 July.; 2 items. (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - The Other World: Essays from the Alternative Society., no date.; 1 item. (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Typescripts of essays.
    - Poetry lectures., 1948 March.; 3 items. (Box 67, Folder 8)
      Typescript of lecture notes: general remarks, Chinese poetry, and folk songs and ballads.
    - Poverty., no date.; ca. 10 items. (Box 67, Folder 9)
      Typewritten and handwritten notes for a KPIX 5 TV program, "Poverty: Crisis in the Affluent Society."
    - Prose I., 1956-1958.; 140 items. (Box 67, Folder 10)
      Material from a binder (labeled as above) containing annotated typescripts of essays and reviews.
    - Prose II., 1956-1958.; 165 items. (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Prose III., 1956-1958.; 120 items. (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Prose IV., 1960.; 150 items. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Random Thoughts About the Times of Sung., 1960.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Bay Guardian., 1969-1972.; ca. 30 items. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Typescripts of columns.
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 1 of 8)., 1960-1961.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Typescripts of columns, bound.
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 2 of 8)., 1961-1962.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 3 of 8)., 1962.; 1 item. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 4 of 8)., 1963.; 1 item. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 5 of 8)., 1964.; 1 item. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 6 of 8)., 1965.; 1 item. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 7 of 8)., 1965.; 1 item. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Highlights (folder 8 of 8)., 1965.; 1 item. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Miscellaneous., ca. 1970.; 1 item. (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - San Francisco Examiner--Trips abroad., 1966-1967.; c. 15 items. (Box 70, Folder 5-6)
    - San Francisco Magazine., 1969-1974.; ca. 100 items. (Box 71, Folder 1-4)
    - San Francisco Ballet., 1965.; 2 items. (Box 71, Folder 5)
      Typescript of program notes for performance at Lincoln Center; supporting documents.
    - Saturday Review piece on California writers., 1967 August 18.; 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Selected Poems of D.H. Lawrence--Introduction., ca. 1947.; 2 items. (Box 71, Folder 7)
      Typescripts and notes. Includes lists of possible selections and outline for essay. Published by New Directions in New York, 1947.
    - Some Thoughts on Jazz As Music, As Revolt, As Mystique., no date.; 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Bureau of Ethnology Collection of American Indian Songs., 1956 January.; 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Vauvenargues., 1958 November.; 2 items. (Box 71, Folder 10)
      Typescript (article for Mademoiselle).
    - A Very Vital Man., no date.; 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 11)
      Essay on Walter Lowenfels.
    - With Eye and Ear., ca. 1959-1970.; 4 items. (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
      Annotated typescripts and proofs.
  - Subseries 3F: Translations,., 1952-1974; 5 boxes.
    Arranged alphabetically, where possible, by the given title of the manuscript or published work.
    - Miscellaneous essays--Unpublished., 1960 March 10.; 1 item. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      Handlist of unpublished essays and reviews.
    - Fourteen Poems by O.V. de L. Milosz., ca. 1952.; 1 item. (Box 72, Folder 5)
      Typescript of French and English verse. Lacking two poems which appear in the published version. Published in San Francisco by the Peregrine Press, 1952.
    - Homero Aridjis--Blue Spaces., ca. 1974.; 1 item. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Homero Aridjis--Selected Poems., ca. 1974.; 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Love in the Turning Year., no date.; 3 items. (Box 73, Folder 2-4)
      Annotated typescripts and drafts.
    - One Hundred Poems from the Chinese., ca. 1956.; 1 item. (Box 74, Folder 1-4)
      Annotated typescripts and galley proofs. First published in New York by New Directions, 1956.
    - One Hundred Poems from the French., ca. 1971.; 3 items. (Box 75, Folder 1-3)
      Translations from 20th century French poets, intended for publication by Jargon Press, but not published. Includes mixed typescripts and handwritten drafts for 1955 edition, and photocopied typescript of 1971 edition.
    - One Hundred Poems from the Japanese., ca. 1955.; 9 items. (Box 75, Folder 4-6)
      Assorted packets of typescripts and handwritten MSS of Japanese poems (including Katue Kitsasono) and English translations; Rexroth's introduction. Includes galley proofs.
    - The Orchid Boat., ca. 1972.; ca. 100 items. (Box 76, Folder 1-6)
      Annotated typescripts and handwritten notes, plus a folder entitled "Texts Chinese Women Ling Chung," with handwritten Chinese texts and translations. See box 158 for annotated galleys.
    - Pierre Reverdy: Selected Poems., ca. 1969.; 2 items. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Poems from the Chinese., 1978 December.; 2 items. (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Rexroth translations set to music by Betty Beath.
    - Poems from the Greek Anthology., no date.; 3 items. (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Typescript, and two Rexroth poems translated into Greek. Includes an introduction by Rexroth. Published in Ann Arbor, Michigan, by the University of Michigan Press, 1962. See box 158 for annotated galleys.
    - Thirty Spanish Poems of Love and Exile., ca. 1956.; 1 item. (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Handwritten draft. First published in San Francisco by the City Lights Pocket Bookshop, 1956 (Pocket Series no. 2).
- Series 4: Manuscripts by others, 1936-1975; 18.5 boxes (9.25 linear ft.).
  Manuscripts by others sent to Kenneth Rexroth, typically for comments, feedback and review.
  A. A-Z, 1936-1975 (17.5 boxes).
  B. Lonergan Conference papers, 1970 (1 box).
  - Subseries 4A: A-Z,., 1936-1975; 17.5 boxes.
    Subseries 4A consists largely of poetry manuscripts submitted to Rexroth for review. Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the author; unidentified manuscripts may be found under "U."
    - Abbott, Keith., 1970.; 3 items. (Box 77, Folder 6)
      Short Change; Blue Blue Blue Suede Shoes
    - Acker, Kathy (aka Black Tarantula)., 1973 July.; 7 items. (Box 77, Folder 7)
      Photocopied and stapled booklets, letters
    - Aldan, Daisy., no date.; 1 item. (Box 77, Folder 8)
      "A Throw of the Dice"
    - Algería, Fernando., 1973 October 24.; 2 items. (Box 77, Folder 9)
      Selections from Amerika Amerikka Amerikkka, translated with a letter by David Smith
    - Amahe, Charlotte., 1952-1953.; 2 items. (Box 77, Folder 10)
      Poems
    - Andalis, Priet., 1962-1964.; 5 items. (Box 77, Folder 11)
      Poems, letters
    - Anderson, Forrest., no date.; 1 item. (Box 77, Folder 12)
      "More Hominium"
    - Anderson, Lee., ca. 1953.; 1 item. (Box 77, Folder 13)
      "The Floating World"
    - Anno, Jaqulin., 1969.; 2 items. (Box 77, Folder 14)
      Poems, letter
    - Anthony, Tom., no date.; 1 item. (Box 77, Folder 15)
      "Hotel: A Sketch"
    - Antler., ca. 1975.; 3 items. (Box 78, Folder 1)
      "Last Words'" poems, letter
    - Archer, Kate Renne., no date.; 1 item. (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Untitled poem
    - Aron, Harry., no date.; 1 item. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Arrowsmith, William., 1960.; 2 items. (Box 78, Folder 4)
      Partial translation of Iliad (Texas Quarterly, v. 2 no. 4); translation of Aristophanes' The Birds
    - Artman, Carol., no date.; 3 items. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      Poems; two letters
    - Atchity, Kenneth., ca. 1973.; 16 items. (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Untitled group of published poems and articles by Atchity
    - Atewart, Barrie., 1969.; 3 items. (Box 78, Folder 7)
      Untitled group of poems, letter
    - Ault, Michael., 1973.; 2 items. (Box 78, Folder 8)
      "Night Wish"; letter
    - Austin, Monica L., 1973 February.; 1 item. (Box 78, Folder 9)
      "A Beautiful Day"
    - Bastian, Richard., 1962 April 25.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Poems and letter
    - Baum, Thomas., 1958.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Beck, Julian., 1953.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Four Songs
    - Beebe, Norman John., 1970.; 2 items. (Box 79, Folder 4)
      "Bright as the Rhyme of the Sun" (collection of poems); letter
    - Bellerophon., 1961.; 2 items. (Box 79, Folder 5)
      "Poetry: A Mock Issue"; Screw: A New Literary Quarterly (parody)
    - Benn, Gottfried., no date.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Bentov, Sharona., 1967.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Bercia, F., no date.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 8)
      "Life in the Solar Plexus: A Scenario"
    - Beye, Holly., no date.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 9)
      Untitled poems
    - Biétry Carlson, Jehanne., 1958 March-April.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 10)
      "Chez Rexroth"
    - Bjerknes, Chris., no date.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 11)
      Assorted poetry
    - Booth, Luella., 1962.; 2 items. (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Bowling, Sam., 1972 April.; 2 items. (Box 79, Folder 13)
      "Looking for Kansas"; letter
    - Branch, James., no date.; 1 item. (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Brown, John Grecen., 1968.; 2 items. (Box 79, Folder 15)